Michael J. Pedersen

42 Henry St Oxford, NJ 07863 m.pedersen@icelus.org (908) 718-1337

Executive Summary

A Systems Administrator with over 15 years of experience managing Windows, Linux, UNIX, and Macintosh systems. A strong focus on writing programs to make processes easier and more efficient for the entire work force. Comfortable in a wide range of working conditions. Work environments have been heterogeneous (Windows, OSX, and several flavors of Linux), small to medium sized (from 10 to 120 servers, 20 to 300 workstations), and mixed locations (all local to all remote teams).

Relevant Work History

Open Source Software Contributions

2002-Current

- Starting in 2009, I began participating in the <u>TurboGears</u> project, working primarily on the documentation. In 2011, I took over as project maintainer, and we put out three releases in that year alone.
- \bullet Contributed documentation to \underline{WebGUI} project, showing how to design a custom theme for \underline{WebGUI}
- Contributed documentation to <u>libpqxx</u> project, showing how to compile <u>libpqxx</u> using <u>MinGW/MSys</u> on <u>Windows</u>.

Choopa.com, Sayreville, NJ - Developer

2012

- Configured <u>Bacula</u> backup system as replacement for custom backup scripts.
- Reconfigured <u>Nagios</u> monitoring system, reducing full systems check from 8 hours to 2 minutes.
- Built <u>Nagios</u> configuration file generator for in-house web interface for <u>Nagios</u>.

6th Avenue Electronics, Springfield, NJ - Systems Administrator, IT Generalist 2005-2008, 2011

- Successfully lead migration from SAP to Tyler Point of Sale system.
- Created automation scripts to easily reconfigure hundreds of terminal definitions within <u>Tyler</u> that could not be done via simple data import.
- Wrote automated installer for the <u>Tyler</u> client program to incorporate the program plus the mandatory pieces that we needed.
- Installed and configured **Zenoss** for full systems monitoring.
- Implemented <u>VMWare</u> Virtual Infrastructure 3.
- Maintained <u>Tyler</u> point of sale system on <u>HP-UX</u> (and, later, Linux), responsible for inventory, sales, purchasing, and accounting for the entire company.
- Developed workaround to resolve issue in point of sales system causing store wide sales terminal lockups.
- Maintained heterogeneous environment with more than 60 Linux and more than 40 Windows servers.
- Maintained <u>CommVault</u> backup system and disaster recovery site.

Datapipe, Inc., Jersey City, NJ - UNIX Developer

2008-2011

- Optimized <u>PostgreSQL</u> database on <u>FreeBSD</u>. Multi-million record insert jobs were taking hours to complete, and the optimization brought that time down to 20 minutes.
- Created internal packages for <u>Bacula</u> (internal name: SureRestore) for all supported platforms.
- Evaluated potential replacements for Subversion, including Git and Mercurial.

Specific Skills

Operating Systems Used / Administered

	Time Used	Last Used	Proficiency
Linux (<u>Debian</u> , <u>RedHat</u> , SuSE)	13 years	2012	Excellent
UNIX (<u>Solaris</u> , <u>AIX</u> , <u>HP-UX</u>)	5 years	2011	Very Good
Microsoft Windows (2008/7/Vista/2003/XP/NT/98/95)	12 years	2011	Very Good

Programming and Scripting Languages

	Time Used	Last Used	Proficiency
<u>Bash</u>	6 years	2011	Good
<u>Perl</u>	6 years	2012	Good
Python Python	4 years	2012	Very Good

Database Servers

	Time Used	Last Used	Proficiency
<u>PostgreSQL</u>	5 years	2011	Good
Microsoft SQL Server	3 years	2008	Fair
MySQL	1 year	2012	Fair

Applications

	Time Used	Last Used	Proficiency
<u>Ipswitch</u> What's Up	2 years	2008	Good
<u>Nagios</u>	3 years	2012	Good
<u>OpenStack</u>	<1 year	2012	Fair
<u>VMWare</u>	6 years	2011	Very Good
Zenoss	<1 year	2011	Fair

Networking and Security

	Time Used	Last Used	Proficiency
Checkpoint VPN	2 years	2007	Fair
Cisco	3 years	2011	Fair
Firewall Design	5 years	2011	Good
TCP/IP	10 years	2011	Very Good

Education

East Stroudsburg University, East Stroudsburg, Pennsylvania Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Graduated

2000

Project History

SAP to Tyler Conversion

Period 2011

Company 6th Avenue Electronics

Tools <u>AutoIt3</u>, <u>CentOS</u> Linux, <u>Python</u>

Platform Server: <u>CentOS</u> Linux, Client: <u>Windows</u>

6th Avenue Electronics found that <u>SAP</u> was not a workable solution for them. The decision was made to switch back to the <u>Tyler</u> POS system. They would do a new installation, though, so that mistakes made with the old system could be removed, and the system could be more easily maintained. I was tapped to manage many of the technical aspects of the migration, while my immediate managers would handle the business aspects.

Due to the costs associated with <u>SAP</u>, we had just over three months, in total, to complete the transition. We were successful.

- Wrote several one-off scripts to check data that was sent in various Excel spreadsheets. Validate that all entries in column A of File 1/Sheet 1 are in Column C of File 2/Sheet 1.
- Used <u>AutoIt3</u> to automate the update of several items that could only be keyed into the client. No import existed at all. This reduced work from several hours down to an hour (including the initial script creation).
- Developed an automated installer that was used to handle installing all components (receipt printer, fonts, initial configuration) on every machine in the company.
- Worked with <u>Tyler</u> Retail Systems to configure the server properly.
- Developed snapshot backup strategy that reduces downtime for <u>Tyler</u> to mere minutes per night.

VMWare Implementation

Period 2005-2007

Company 6th Avenue Electronics

Tools <u>VMWare</u> Virtual Infrastructure 3, <u>VMWare</u> Virtual Center

Platform Linux (Various distributions), Windows Server 2003

6th Avenue Electronics, like many companies, had a growing need for individual servers for various internal services. They chose to implement <u>VMWare</u> to reduce hardware costs, downtime, and environmental costs.

- Installed and configured iSCSI based SAN disks.
- Installed and configured all aspects of \underline{VMWare} Virtual Center and \underline{VMWare} Virtual Infrastructure 3.
- Developed (and tested) virtual machine templates to allow rapid deployment of new virtual servers using various operating systems (<u>Windows</u> XP, <u>Windows</u> 2003, <u>Debian</u> GNU/Linux, RedHat Linux).
- Monitored daily usage of <u>VMWare</u> hosts.